# THOMAS TESFALDET

## WEB DEVELOPER

■ thomas.tesfaldet@mail.utoronto.ca soriphen.github.io/thomas-portfolio/ 447-928-4239 Toronto, Canada

in /in/thomas-tesfaldet soriphen

#### **SUMMARY**

A web developer specializing in the MongoDB, Express, React and Node is stack. A minimalist driven by a design philosophy: light, fast, reliable and style. Passionate in creating applications with eye-catching simplicity, yet robust features. I strive to construct the perfect user experience; succinct and accessible interfaces, intuitive to use on all platforms

#### **SKILLS**

FRONTEND: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Bootstrap 5, Tone.is, p5.js, D3.js, Redux, jQuery, React Native, Chakra UI, SCSS, Puq, styled components, Expo

BACKEND: Node.is, Express, Mongoose, Chair

DATABASE: MongoDB, Firebase OTHER: Git, ZenHub, Glide

LANGUAGES: English, Japanese, Tigrinya

### **EMPLOYMENT**

Consoul, Junior React Native Developer, Toronto, ON

Jan. 2022 - Current

- Designed and implemented authentication module with firebase integration for both iOS and Android apps.
- Contributed to architectural design decisions and implemented said designs (custom drawer, redux implementation, etc.) to apps, as well as participating and collaborating in feature discovery discussions
- Core developer for working on MVP -- responsible for setting goals for deliverables and achieving them.
- Collaborated with co-developer with weekly code-alonas.
- · Described processes/updates in layman terms for management as well as in technical terms for co-developer during weekly meetings

Canada Papers, Shopify Web Store Designer & Developer, 386 Watline Ave, Mississauga, ON L4Z 1X2

June 2021 - Current

- · Assisted in designing the web storefront by creating and organizing product listings.
- Employed proper SEO practices with product listings resulting in attracting our first customer
- Translated and transferred CSV files from existing Amazon storefront to the correct Shopify CSV format.
- Frequently updated product pricing and inventory to accurately reflect those sold at physical storefront.

### **PROJECTS**

**Drum Step Sequencer** June 2021 - Aug. 2021

Using React, tone.js, and p5.js, developed a 16 step sequencer with an audio visualizer and sounds created from a digital audio workstation.

- The user would click on boxes which would store audio in a multidimensional array to be played through integration of tone.js.
- The user would be able to select which group of samples to play for any row, preserving sample placement from previous selection. Added the ability to add/remove rows for additional samples to be played.
- Integrated tone.js with React and p5.js to create a seamless interaction where waveform data extracted by tone.js is passed by React to be drawn by p5.js in real-time to create an audio visualizer reactive to outputted sound.

Markdown Previewer May 2021 - June 2021

Using React, created a responsive markdown previewer integrated with Ace Editor.

- · Developed a mobile-responsive input/output markdown processor with live-preview functionality
- Successfully integrated JavaScript libraries highlight.js with marked.js to be used within react-ace in order to properly convert a written code-block in markdown to JavaScript syntax highlighting
- Integrated react-ace in order to implement the functionality and design of modern code editors with features such as: gutters, line numbering, markdown syntax highlighting, active line highlighting, and foldina.

Student Profile Search Sept. 2021 - Sept. 2021

Using React, designed and developed a mobile-responsive search filter using a mock list of student profiles fetched from an API endpoint.

- · Implemented a tag feature that allows a user to create as many of their own removable tags and attach them to a student profile for search filtering.
- · Developed a search name feature that filters by a student's first name, or last name, or both through regex Developed a search tag feature that filters through created tags and can be used for search filtering in combination with the search name bar.

Oct. 2021 - Oct. 2021 **URL Shortener Microservice** 

Using Node.js, Express, Mongoose, and MongoDB, developed a microservice API that shortens a URL.

- · Implemented the validator, js library for validating inputted URLs, otherwise returning a JSON with proper error messaging.
- Integrated with MongoDB to produce a real-time updating database for storage of short URL values
- Using Mongoose, implemented an increment feature where each subsequent short value in the database is increased so as to give each new document a unique short URL.

#### **EDUCATION**

JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures Certification 2021 Back End Development and APIs Certification 2021

https://www.freecodecamp.org/soriphen

#### Juno College

Web Development Course 2020

#### University of Toronto

Bachelor of Arts (Honours) East Asian Studies 2019

Kwansei Gakuin University

Participant in the Global Career Seminar -- worked with Orix Corporation and Japanese peers to solve an industry problem and deliver a presentation of my findings in a formal Japanese setting

July 2018 - Aug. 2018

Studied abroad to Akita International University for 1 year through University of Toronto

Sept. 2016 - Sept. 2017